<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Cultures and Family Business</title>
    <link>http://onescenario.com</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 23:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why studying culture in family business?—A personal view</title>
      <link>http://onescenario.com/writing/why-studying-culture-in-family-business-a-personal-view</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 23:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rocky Adiguna</author>
      <guid>http://onescenario.com/writing/why-studying-culture-in-family-business-a-personal-view</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Why culture?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the business world, but I don’t like if it is too much about money and profit. For me, business entity as a form of organization contains much more purpose than just for pursuing economic ends. I view it as a place of interaction where there are agreements and conflicts, understanding and misunderstanding, similarities and differences, and any sorts of activities that make life more fulfilling or even dulling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given this richness, my underlying interest of doing research is to understand the (social) world itself. In organizational context, this is translated to questions like: what does it mean to be organized? What does it mean to organize? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that the foundational way to understand this issue is through the cultural lens. To the best of my knowledge, culture theories provide ways of framing the basic assumptions a given group has, their values, norms, and behaviors. Culture also serves as a framework that people use to interpret their environment. How to adapt and survive. So, given the importance of culture in human interaction, I believe that there is much to be learned if I do research on (organizational) culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why in family business?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be useful to borrow Berger &amp;amp; Luckmann’s (1967)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; explanation on how culture is formed and perceived differently by the founding generation and their descendants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a case of two persons A and B:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As A and B interact, in whatever manner, typifications will be produced quite quickly. A watches B perform. He attributes motives to B’s actions and, seeing the actions recur, typifies the motives as recurrent. As B goes on performing, A is soon able to say to himself, ‘Aha, there he goes again.’ At the same time, A may assume that B is doing the same thing with regard to him. From the beginning, both A and B assume this reciprocity of typification. In the course of their interaction these typifications will be expressed in specific patterns of conduct. That is, A and B will begin to play roles &lt;em&gt;vis-a-vis&lt;/em&gt; each other. (p. 74)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then when the next generation appears:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us push our paradigm one step further and imagine that A and B have children. At this point the situation changes qualitatively. The appearance of a third party changes the character of the ongoing social interaction between A and B, and it will change even further as additional individuals continue to be added. (pp. 75&amp;ndash;76)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example above illustrates how generational issue becomes an important aspect when speaking about culture. To understand how the culture is formed, modified and perpetuated, we need to take into account the inter-generational interaction in the family. This&amp;mdash;the family&amp;mdash;is the first layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second layer is the business aspect of the family business. As a business entity, it has another reason of being: to engage in economic activity. So the kind of interactions that a family business is involved is much wider and more complex than a mere family or business institution. This combination of the two spheres, then, further complicate the culture that may arise from such interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why visual ethnography? (and a bit about myself)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my interest in visual methods/ethnography can be linked back to my personal interest in visual media such as graphic design, photography and videography. I used to run a start-up that produces promotional (and also documentary) videos and designs. Since my undergraduate years, I love taking pictures and making short films. So back then I thought, why not build a company out of these?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then after finishing my bachelor, I took a master degree in entrepreneurship at Jönköping International Business School, Sweden. There I had a chance to officially register my start-up (called “&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/hompimpa&quot;&gt;Hompimpa Creativeworks&lt;/a&gt;”) and worked on several projects in Jönköping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years later, I obtained my master degree and aspired to continue for a PhD. Long story short, I was interviewed by Denise and offered a PhD position at the University of Luxembourg. I accepted her offer and consequently decided to close my start-up to focus on the PhD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Denise recognized my skills and interest in videography and photography. I’m very lucky, I have to say. Some weeks after Denise announced my acceptance as her PhD student, she suggested me to take a look on visual sociology/visual methods. When I did the search, I was blown away. I did not know such thing exists before, and visual methods is a perfect combination of the worlds that I am interested in: academic research &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; visual media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I guess the excitement has been growing from there. This PhD becomes more like a personal fulfillment, if I can put it that way, where I can pour in my dedication into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then finally, after I moved to Luxembourg and officially work at the university, I learned that we need two internal supervisors and one external supervisor. For the external one, we agreed to include Leif Melin (he is a professor from Jönköping International Business School, Sweden). Then for the internal one, we were thinking to have a perspective outside of the business management field. Insofar, family business studies have been borrowing theories from the field of culture, but it seems that the contribution that family business field can give back to the field of cultural studies is still very limited. That is why we are so glad that &lt;a href=&quot;http://wwwen.uni.lu/recherche/flshase/education_culture_cognition_and_society_eccs/people/ingrid_de_saint_georges&quot;&gt;Ingrid de Saint-Georges&lt;/a&gt; is interested to join the team. I’ve taken a quick look to her papers and I was amazed to think about the potentials of what we can do together. Discourse analysis, visual ethnography, family business. Fascinating!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berger, P. L., &amp;amp; Luckmann, T. (1967). &lt;em&gt;The Social Construction of Reality: A Treatise in the Sociology of Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Anchor Books.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture as they see it</title>
      <link>http://onescenario.com/writing/culture-as-they-see-it</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 11:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rocky Adiguna</author>
      <guid>http://onescenario.com/writing/culture-as-they-see-it</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This time I asked my fellows about what culture is to them. Why? After months of reading the literature about culture in organizations, I feel as if that the more I read, the more I lose what it means. Getting too close to the subject makes you can’t see what it is! (A friend said: it is a true and empirically testable statement)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, as a way to distance myself a little bit, I thought that it would be helpful if I ask a person outside of the field about what &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; think about culture. Because sometimes, the best ideas come from an area different from yours. It turned out to be quite refreshing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is no right or wrong here. I was looking for their interpretation when they encounter something as ‘cultural’. Anything is valid from their own perspective.
No need to prolong, below are the excerpt of their answers to my question: &lt;strong&gt;what does it mean to you when you see something as ‘cultural’?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The answers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yugo Risfriwan.&lt;/strong&gt; A filmmaker based in Indonesia. He is practically my go-to person whenever I had a weird thought and need an external point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It means that it has been done by &lt;em&gt;kebiasaan&lt;/em&gt; [habit], by generations of people that came before. But &lt;em&gt;membudaya&lt;/em&gt; [cultural] isn’t always something positive, it could even be destructive, people do it because they see other people before them doing it making it either a norm, or just plain habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We slowly adapt to them, like an organism that moves from his original habitat to another. In a social context I guess it’s the same concept. If we don’t adapt we will be outcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can analyze deeper, I think cultural things emerge mostly and firstly because of the environment/surroundings of that society. Maybe we can take an example of two groups. The mountain people and the beach people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example for beach people, the men tend to be fisherman and small boys wish to be a fisherman. Mothers would encourage their sons to go fishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the mountains, they would have to &lt;em&gt;berkebun&lt;/em&gt; [farm].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats a really raw example, really. But I think when you trace back, it tends to come to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in &lt;em&gt;budaya&lt;/em&gt; [culture] that has to do with art. Since in certain parts of the world they only have that one certain raw material. If wood is plenty, they make wooden statues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, we don’t have the travel limit anymore. There are tons of export and import of many societies mixing together. Sort of like hybrid cultures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at its base, I think why a certain culture exists is because it’s what came naturally. Because it was easy. Because it was accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting that he raises up the issues of:  (1) generations, (2) practice over time, (3) taken-for-grantedness, and (4) physical constraints. Culture is seen as a way to adapt to the environment that makes it easy for the coming generations to cope with it (so they can just do the work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alfatika Aunuriella Dini.&lt;/strong&gt; A PhD student in Norway. She is Yugo’s wife, and what I love with this couple is their criticality. So, it just went naturally that I have to ask her too about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is shared values, visible by repetitive action and embedded in a particular social construction/organization. It can also be in a form of cultural artifact like song, clothing, paintings, artworks, etc. And it’s constantly changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But can it also be ‘identity’?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm, interesting twist. That’s also what the scholars are currently debating: is identity part of culture or is it something different?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abshir Sharif.&lt;/strong&gt; A freelance supply chain consultant based in the Netherlands. He is my philosophical sparing partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me when I hear culture, I relate to the specifics of people, society and organizations, a period in time, that means the norms on how they behave, the ethics of good of bad or aspects of their lives based on their circumstances around them that define their beliefs, emotions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in short I would say, culture is the norms that guide our thoughts and behavior, it can be associated to specific period in time, or an organization, or people in a society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is system of ideas, customs and behaviors that is build together collectively through interactions and over a period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the issue of ‘time dimension’ (happening over time) is brought up, along with ‘norms that drive behaviors’, and ‘organizational or societal context’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ni Zhen.&lt;/strong&gt; A PhD student in Luxembourg. She is my workmate with a research focus on innovation. Apart from research, she is also an avid art appreciator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think culture is, if I have to define rigorously, something that distinguishes human from animals, a complex system of symbols and interpretations of symbols. And they all inevitably involve some degree of intelligence and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting! Symbols and interpretations of symbols. So I would translate this that culture is something ‘out there’ (outside of oneself, a symbolic representation) as well as something ‘inside here’ (inside of the self, a symbolic interpretation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ferdinand Padang.&lt;/strong&gt; A master student in Sweden. He has worked several years for a large private company in Indonesia, and is currently taking his master degree on entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that appears to me, I’ll come up with a thought: should I follow or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then it depends on the importance of that cultural matter. If it’s not critical for me, then it’s considered negligible [for me to follow or not].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corruption, for example. People said that it is cultural [in Indonesia]. For me when seeing that, I think there must be a reason [for that to happen].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A different point of view. The way I interpret this is that—for him—the term ‘culture’ itself is not problematic (presumably defined in a wide sense). And the concern is more on how the “I” should react on a particular cultural practice, if it matters. Should I adopt it, should I not? Understanding the ‘reason’ behind certain practices will help the reflexive self to decide whether that practices appropriate or not to be reproduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Wrapping up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culture is a wide term that can mean anything. I’m surprised, really. People are virtually able to theorize about culture—you don’t need to be a PhD in this field to theorize about it! Maybe if I were to answer my own question, I would find myself stuttering just to start my first sentence. Then the question for me is, what difference would it make if my research is about (organizational) culture? A homework to be thought through.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28th RENT Conference - Luxembourg: Takeaways</title>
      <link>http://onescenario.com/writing/28th-rent-conference-luxembourg-takeaways</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rocky Adiguna</author>
      <guid>http://onescenario.com/writing/28th-rent-conference-luxembourg-takeaways</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From November 19th until 21st 2014, RENT XXVIII (Research in Entrepreneurship and Small Business) was my first conference I had attended. It was a great experience. Not only because I was one of the participants, but also because I was quite involved in organizing the conference. The feedback was good. People were generally satisfied with the conference, which I found to be quite relieving given that our team&amp;mdash;the organizer&amp;mdash;were rather spartan. Only 5 or 6 people organizing the whole event. Small team but solid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a participant, I found this conference to be an eye opener. Great people, great ideas, and very inspirational. And here are my takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Family tree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a newbie in the circle of entrepreneurship research, I started to experience how it feels to be connected to the leading scholars. It’s true, your proximity to these people will bestow you with some degree of inspiration and motivation. When I wrote my doctoral proposal, for example, I was largely inspired by Mats Alvesson’s writings on organizational culture. At the conference, I did not have the chance to see Mats (and he wasn’t attending the conference either), but what I did have a chance was to meet &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbs.dk/en/research/departments-and-centres/department-of-management-politics-and-philosophy/staff/dhmpp&quot;&gt;Daniel Hjorth&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lu.se/lucat/user/091f4799ef44464bd39adb572fc5c3a3&quot;&gt;Mats Alvesson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://lnu.se/employee/bengt.johannisson?l=en&quot;&gt;Bengt Johannisson&lt;/a&gt; were his supervisors back in his PhD days. It’s not the source, but despite that I felt there was energy emanating from him to me (no exaggeration intended).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Bengt, I first met him when he was teaching at Jönköping International Business School (JIBS). In entrepreneurship research, he has been well-regarded and famous (among other things) for his “entrepreneuring” point of view. He was retired few years ago, but still very active in research at Linneæus University, Växjö, Sweden (I’m sure he will never stop researching). To me, he is a figure who wakes entrepreneurship, breathes entrepreneurship, sleeps entrepreneurship&amp;mdash;quite literally, everything he does turns into entrepreneurship. Denise Fletcher, my supervisor, said that Bengt was the one who inspired her towards the critical perspective on entrepreneurship when she attended her first RENT conference in 1996.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/IMG_1919.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Daniel Hjorth&quot;&gt;Daniel Hjorth asks a question on the keynote session with Martin Ruef.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference was held a week after &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onescenario.com/writing/andrew-pettigrews-message-to-young-scholars/&quot;&gt;Andrew Pettigrew’s seminar&lt;/a&gt; at JIBS. From the hindsight, I see these two events as an eye opener. First, that I got to meet the scholars whose writings I can only read before. Meeting these people in person and have a dialogue with them really helps to motivate and inspire you. You began to see a wider landscape of entrepreneurship research (and researchers). Second, because you are connected with these people, you started to contemplate on your potential as a doctoral student in the field&amp;mdash;what kind of career do you want to choose and what kind of impact do you want to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you meet the teachers of your teachers, you feel like you are in the lineage of something. You feel like being part of the family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Naïvety or bravery?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to raise this question whenever I had a chance to seek advice from people. As a (doctoral) student, I think we are fated to be naive. Because the lack of experience, we may think big but occasionally failed to appreciate the difficulty in achieving that goals. We know little but act as if we can change the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there any way to reduce this? How can we know that our research idea is a form of bold and brave thinking, or is it a naive shot of the inexperienced? How can we be brave while being not too naive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s a hard question,” replied Daniel Hjorth. “But the kind of readings you read will help you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, reading about philosophy. Well, Daniel doesn’t recommend us to read Foucault or Bourdieu directly from the source. Not only that it is difficult to read, but there are some language that we (non-philosophy student) simply don’t have the vocabulary. Instead, it is advised that we read the interpretations of such and such authors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By understanding the philosophical grounding of your research, it will help you to be sensitive about the knowledge about knowledge. It is the critical quality when you are able to distance yourself from your thinking and see how you see yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But please be careful when you are absolutely sure about your way of thinking. When your way becomes &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; way. That is a sign that things get settled. And when you are settled, you stop to appreciate other alternatives. And when you stop, you don’t make progress. Conviction is necessary for the faith to blossom, but doubt is needed for the faith to be healthy and sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bengt took a slightly different angle to answer these. As a doctoral student, he said, you are not expected to change the world. Well, of course you need to make a contribution. But the expectation for contribution is certainly less than the professors in the field. &lt;em&gt;They&lt;/em&gt; need to change the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather, at the very basic, you have to learn the craft. The basic skills of research, writing, and presenting the work. These are the homework that you have to master before you can start being ‘playful’. Just like when &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/HdZp36I8oZc&quot;&gt;Mozart ‘improvises’ on Salieri’s composition&lt;/a&gt;, he firstly needs to master Salieri’s composition before playing around with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But can we really play as a student? Bengt once talked about how his students commented to him, “You are a professor, you can do whatever you want. But we are just a student [so we have rules to obey].”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to improvise when we don’t grasp the rudiments of research. By mastering the basics, we will be able to see how the current practice could be changed—that would be our own angle. No one learns the same way (even from the same teacher). It is our own framing and interpretation of a phenomenon which makes our thoughts unique. Which we hope will be our contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/IMG_1714.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bengt Johannisson&quot;&gt;
Bengt Johannisson presents his ongoing work on identity and legitimacy.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The triangle of career, institution and publication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, as a doctoral student, you are faced with one pressing question: where do you want to go after your PhD life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; life after PhD, said &lt;a href=&quot;http://findresearcher.sdu.dk:8080/portal/en/persons/martin-hannibal(ae9f6713-1aa7-4fdb-8d7c-f935bd507128).html&quot;&gt;Martin Hannibal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pure.au.dk/portal/en/stk@badm.au.dk&quot;&gt;Steffen Korsgaard&lt;/a&gt;, they kicked-off the pre-conference event with a doctoral workshop, something of a tradition within the RENT conference. There they gave their straight-forward and pragmatic point of view on the relationship between career choice, the institution that you are working, and the pressure for publication. I found this to be fresh and revealing. It was more like an honest conversation between the seniors and juniors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/IMG_1516.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Martin Hannibal&quot;&gt;
Martin Hannibal on the RENT doctoral workshop.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/IMG_1723.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_1723&quot;&gt;
Steffen Korsgaard as a session chair on critical perspective of entrepreneurship.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer to settle down in the university where you are working, then you need to conform with the institutional system, understand the formal and informal rules, accept some degree of teaching responsibility, and aim less for publishing. Or maybe you prefer to work at the best business school in Europe or the US? That’s fine too. Then you need to get published on the A+ journal (presumably with less teaching load) while it is not really necessary to conform with the institution (given that you will move pretty fast between different institutions). For those who are in between, good luck balancing the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me the message is clear: (1) you need to ask yourself what is valuable for you, and (2) you need to find it early in the process. Because whatever that is, it will affect any decision you will make about your research, your publication, and your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, it was a great experience. With now the conference is over, it is time to get back to work, read, and write. I hope by the next conference I can have something that I can present. As a present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Pettigrew’s message to young scholars</title>
      <link>http://onescenario.com/writing/andrew-pettigrews-message-to-young-scholars</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Rocky Adiguna</author>
      <guid>http://onescenario.com/writing/andrew-pettigrews-message-to-young-scholars</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This time &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Pettigrew&quot;&gt;Andrew Pettigrew&lt;/a&gt;, a world-renowned management professor from Saïd Business School University of Oxford, came to JIBS for a seminar in the second part of Strategy as Process and Practice course. In his energetic, provocative, and occasionally humorous style, Andrew shared his point of view on process scholarship as well as scholarship in general. Here is my interpretation of his advises for young scholars (especially PhD students)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Don’t put yourself in a box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, ontological (philosophical) box. “It’s unnecessary,” Andrew said. “It invites people to have a go at you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a PhD student, you are still in the beginning of the beginning of your career. Claiming that you are a ‘critical realist’ or ‘social constructionist’ or whatever will restrict yourself to that box. And in reality, you are not entirely standing on this or that paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you claim that you are, let’s say, a critical realist, you expose yourself to unnecessary problems. And there are so many versions of critical realism. Which one is yours? Do you really know what critical realism is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To claim an identity requires others to acknowledge it. As a beginner in the academic career, you don’t have the intellectual capital that legitimates your claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of claiming, Andrew advises you to focus in doing the best work at the highest quality you can do. Label comes and go and it could be just a fad. “Don’t jump on band wagons. Fads create ten careers and destroy 200 careers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t label yourself. It’s others’ business to label you anything, not you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step away from dichotomy, embrace duality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is not induction or deduction, it is induction &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; deduction. It is not just exploration or exploitation, it is exploration and exploitation. It is not just agency or structure, it agency and structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, dichotomy helps to make contrast. Its power is in the simplicity. People can easily understand the concept and it is theoretically appealing to be indulged in the extremes. But in reality, these dichotomies coexist more like a continuum. Don’t be trapped in the mindset of ‘either-or’, try to think of ‘and’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew would tease you, “Even the old Karl Marx has three (thesis, antithesis, synthesis), why would you divide the world only into two?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Understand the mechanisms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A regression only tells you about a relation between two variables: “If you wind a watch it will keep running.” Mechanisms, on the other hand, pry the back off the watch and show us &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a process scholar, the overriding purpose is to generate ‘how to’ knowledge to complement the predominant ‘what is knowledge&amp;#39; in the social science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A mechanism is about the cogs and wheels, the wheel-work of agency by which an effect is produced.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew is an antique collector, so he is quite fond of a watch metaphor to explain this. It is not enough to merely know the parts making up a watch. More than that, you need to understand how each part is interconnected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Go for an interesting issue, not a trivial one&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is an interesting issue? It is an issue that include some outcome in the analysis and try to link patterns in the observed context and process to variations in the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew also said that his works are always issue-driven. Meaning that there are real practical and social issues that he tries to address. Some examples are: Why high-performing companies constantly outperform low-performing companies? In the case of closing down a hospital, why it takes 15 years to close down a hospital in this municipality and only 6 years in that municipality? These questions imply the need to understand ‘when’ and ‘how’ to explain ‘why’ there are outcome differentials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you can, compacting the research question in this form will help you to link the context, the process, and the outcome. This also implies that studying single company is not enough (or impactful, as Andrew would use the word). Your analyses should incorporate multiple contexts within and &lt;em&gt;between&lt;/em&gt; the firms or organizations. Context, process and outcome studies are attention directors in scholarly and policy arenas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s interesting!” Andrew would say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Throughout your PhD, what point of view have you developed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a ‘trouser-around-the-ankle moment’ for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a ‘final bomb’ Andrew would ask if he is an external examiner of a PhD student. Inability to answer this question implies that you haven’t yet gone above your thesis. Your view is still limited inside your own work. You are still boxed in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing a point of view means you are transcending above and beyond your research to something in a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a good news. Andrew won’t drop this bomb unless he sees that you are capable enough to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is written as a reflection for the second three-day session on “Strategy as Practice/Process” PhD course at Jönköping International Business School, Sweden. The upcoming (final) session will be held on December.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy-as-process and practice: A short reflection</title>
      <link>http://onescenario.com/writing/strategy-as-process-and-practice-a-short-reflection</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 10:51:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Rocky Adiguna</author>
      <guid>http://onescenario.com/writing/strategy-as-process-and-practice-a-short-reflection</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strategy as process and practice calls for a change of perspective in understanding strategy&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Through this way of seeing, strategy is no longer something that an organization has, but it is something an organization do. Strategy is no longer exclusive to the top management, but it is widespread to virtually anyone within the organization. Everyone is a potential strategist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategy as practice perspective brings with it a political message: liberation and democratization of every organizational member to make difference. It is an organizational-level acknowledgment of chaos theory, where a flap of a butterfly can cause a hurricane at the other end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategy as practice comes with power. But it also pushes the responsibility down where everyone is accountable. It is great, but also scary. Not only for practitioners, but also researchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For researchers, strategy as practice perspective means that they need to be aware of whatever is happening within the organization. Be it people’s talk in the corridor, negotiation in the board room, or even a mingle at the coffee table. Remember, strategic actors can be anyone and strategic arenas can be anywhere. It is scary because there are so much that you can get, yet so much that you can lose if you miss one moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key, then, is to capture the fluidity, the tension, the flow. Hence, time dimension is inherent and inseparable in practice perspective. Applying this perspective means giving voice to variance and inconsistency as well as ample dose of sensemaking as, from time to time, organizations are changing and their change is not always coherent and make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is written as a reflection for the first three-day session on “Strategy as Practice/Process” PhD course at Jönköping International Business School, Sweden. The course was led by Leif Melin (day one), Ethel Brundin (day two) and Olof Brunninge (day three). The upcoming sessions will be held on November and December.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; rev=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
